<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>African Tulip Tree</name>
		<sci_name>Spathodea campanulata||Spathodea danckelmaniana||Spathodea nilotica||Spathodea tulipifera</sci_name>
		<common_name>African Tulip Tree (engl)||Fire Tree (engl)||Flame of the Forest (engl)||Fountain Tree (Engl.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>BENGALI: Rudra palash.||CHINESE: Huo yan mu, Cu ye jiu ping shu (Taiwan)_, Ao zhou huo yan shu (Taiwan).||FRENCH: Tulipier du Gabon.||GERMAN: Afrikanischer Tulpenbaum.||HINDI: Rugtoora.||JAPANESE: Kaenboku.||KANNADA: Neerukayi mara.||MALAY: Panchut-panchut.||MALAYALAM: Phaauntanmaram. Sphaathhoodiya, Sukoottamaram.||MARATHI: Akash shevga.||PORTUGUESE: Bisnagueira, Espatódea, Tulipeira-da-África.||RUSSIAN: Spatodeia kolokol´chataia.||SINHALESE: Kudaella gaha, Kudulu.||SPANISH: Amapola, Espatodea, Mampolo, Tulipán africano.||SWAHILI: Kibobakasi, Kifabakazi.||SWEDISH: Afrikanskt tulpanträd.||TAMIL: Patadi.||THAI: Kae sàet.</vernacular>
		<properties>Spathodea campanulata is a robust tree, growing to a height of 20 meters, with a dense, dark, shining, green crown. Leaves are pinnately compound, 20 to 25 centimeters long, divided into 5 to 8 pairs of leaflets. Leaflets are elliptic-oblong, 7.5 to 11 centimeters long, and 3.5 to 7 centimeters wide, with a pointed tip, and several glands along the midrib near the base. Flowers are large, bell-shaped, up to 10 centimeters long and 5 centimeters wide, borne in terminal, erect inflorescences (racemes), with a peculiar smell. Calyx is spathe-lke, strongly curved, brownish, velvety-smooth, and split nearly to the base on one side. Corolla is curved, the tube being narrow below, but strongly inflated and 5-lobed above, scarlet or crimson red, with yellow, frilled edges. Pods are firm, thick, dark-brown, and 15 to 20 centimeters long. Seed is about 2.5 centimeters wide, with a broad, silvery white, transparent wing.</properties>
		<usage>No reported folkloric use in the Philippines.||Bark is commonly used as a dressing for ulcers and skin diseases, applied dried, pulverized, or as fresh inner bark. A leaf decoction is used as lotion.||In Africa, the stem bark is used as a paste for wound healing.||In Senegal, bruised leaves and flowers are applied to wounds.||In Gabon, flowers are applied to ulcers.||In Southern Nigeria, leaves used for convulsions.||In Gold Coast, bark decoction taken for constipation and gastrointestinal problems and dysentery.||Cold infusion of leaves used for urethral inflammation.||In Ghana, the stem bark and leaf used for treatment of dyspepsia and peptic ulcer; leaf, root bark and fruit used for arthritis and fractures; the stem bark used for toothaches and stomachaches; root bark sneed used for stomach ulcers.||In Rwanda, decoction of stem bark used for diabetes.||In Ayurveda, used for kidney diseases. the fluid like water pistols.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted.</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>