<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Ubi-ubihan</name>
		<sci_name>Dioscorea bulbifera||Dioscorea heterophylla||Dioscorea latifolia||Dioscorea oppositifolia||Dioscorea sativa||Dioscorea violacea||Dioscorrea tamifolia||Helmia bulbifera||Huang du</sci_name>
		<common_name>Aribukbuk (Ilk.)||Bayag-kabayo (Tag.)||Dadakan (Bag.)||Pulugan (Bik.)||Ubi-ubihan (Tag.)||Utong-utoñgan (Tag.)||Aerial yam (Engl.)||Air potato (Engl.)||Bitter yam (Engl.)||Potato yam (Engl.)||Huang yao zu (Chin.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>BENGALI: Ban Alu, Rat Alu, Roth Alu.||BURMESE: Ah Lu Thi, Hpwut Sa Uu, Pat Sa Uu.||CHINESE: Shan ci gu, Ling yu shu, Huang yao, Shan ci gu.||FRENCH: Igname Bulbifère, Igname Pousse En L´air, Masako, Pomme En L´air, Pousse En L´air.||GERMAN: Brotwurzel, Kartoffelyam, Knollen-yam, Luft-Kartoffel, Luft-yams, Yamswurzel||HAWAIIAN: Hoi.||HINDI: Gaithi, Hoei Oepas, Karu Kunda, Karukanda, Kodikilangu, Ratalu, Ratula||INIDIA: Hoei-Oepas||JAPANESE: Kashuu Imo, Niga Kashuu.  MARATHI: Kadu Kand, Mataru.||NEPALESE: Giitthaa (Gittha), Giitthe Tarul (Gitthe Tarul), Jada Bis, Van Tarul.||ORIYA: PitaaAlu.||PORTUGUESE: Inhame.||RUSSIAN: Iams Lukovitsenosnyi.||SPANISH: ñame Criollo, ñame De Aire,, ñame De Gunda, ñame Volador, Papa Cimarrona, Papa De Aire.||TELUGU: Adavi Dumpa, Chedupaddudampa, Karu Kanda, Malaka Kayependalamu.||THAI: De Khwa, Ham Pao, La Sa Mi, Lo Chae Mue, Man Khamin, Wan Phra Chim, Wan Sam Phan Thueng||VIETNAMESE: C di, Khoai dái, Khoai tri.</vernacular>
		<properties>Ubi-ubihan is a climbing or twining, dioecious, smooth, unarmed vine reaching a length of several meters. Tubers are rounded, not larger than a man-s fist. Stems are terete, bearing numerous little tubers. Leaves are simple, ovate, 7 to 14 centimeters long, with a broad and prominently heart-shaped base, broad and rounded sinus, rounded lobes, and 7- to 9-nerved. Spikes are slender, panicled, numerous, 8 to 10 centimeters long, and rather densely many-flowered. Flowers are about 3 millimeters long. Capsules are longer than broad. Seeds are winged at the base only. In the wild, tubers, when fresh, are bitter. Cultivated tubers are less or non-bitter. Tubers considered tonic, expectorant, aphrodisiac and anthelmintic.</properties>
		<usage>Tubers taken internally as remedy for dysentery and syphilis.||Tubers used as resolvent for boils and as diuretic.||Powdered tubers used as application for sores, piles and to stop diarrhea.||In India, a folk remedy used to cure wounds, leucoderma and boils. Also, used as tonic, expectorant in asthma, as aphrodisiac and anthelmintic.||In Chinese medicine, used to treat diseases of the lungs, kidney, spleen and many types of diarrhea.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>