<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Sabila</name>
		<sci_name>Aloe barbadensis||Aloe elongata,Aloe humilis||Aloe perfoliata||Aloe vera||Aloe vulgaris</sci_name>
		<common_name>Acibar (Span.)||Dilang-boaia (Bik.)||Dilang buaya (Bik.)||Dilang-halo (Bis.)||Penca sabila (Spanish)||Sabila (Tag.)||Sabila pinya (Tag.)||Barbados aloe (Engl.)||Aloe (English)||Aloe vera (English)||Burn plant (English)||Lu hui (Chin.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>AFRIKAANS: Aalwee, Aalwyn.||BENGALI: Ghrita kumari, Kumari.||DANISH: Lægealoe.||DUTCH: Aloë.||FINNISH: Lääkeaaloe.||FRENCH: Aloès, Aloès vulgaire.||GERMAN: Echte Aloe.||HINDI: Guar patha, Ghikanvar.||ITALIAN: Aloe di Curacao, Aloe delle Barbados, Aloe mediterranea, Aloe vera, Legno aloe.||JAPANESE: Aroe.||KANNADA: Lolisara.||MALAY: Pohon gaharu.||MALAYALAM: Kumari.||MARATHI: Korphad.||NEPALESE: Ghiu kumari.||ORIYA: Kumari.||POLISH: Aloes zwyczajny.||PORTUGUESE: Aloés, Aloé vera, Babosa (Brazil), Aloés de Barbados, Erva-babosa, Azebre Vegetal.||RUSSIAN: Aloe, Aloe nastojašcee ,Aloe vera.||SANSKRIT: Ghirita kumari, Kumari.||SERBIAN: Aloja.||SHONA: Gavakava.||SPANISH: Acíbar, Aloe, Flor do deserto, Loto do deserto, Lináloe, Maguey morado, Penca sábila, Pitera amarelo, Sábila do penca, Sávila, Toots amarelo, Zábila, Zábila dos toots.||SWEDISH: Aloe, Barbados aloe.||TAMIL: Chirukuttali.||TELUGU: Chinna kalabanda.||THAI: Hang ta khe, Wan fai mai, Wan hang chora khe.||TURKISH: Ödagaci., Sarisabir, Sarýsabýr.VIETNAMESE: Cây aloe vera, Cây Lô H?i , Cây Nha Ðam.</vernacular>
		<properties>Sabila is an herb plant growing 30 to 40 centimeters high. Leaves arising from the ground are smooth, fleshy, mucilaginous, succulent, 20 to 50 centimeters long, 5 to 8 centimeters wide, light green with white blotches, arrow-lanceolate, tapering, spiny-toothed margins. Flowering stalk is erect, usually twice the height of the plant. Flowers are 2 to 3 centimeters long, yellow, with segments that about equals the oblong tube.||Not for internal use.||Some mineral cytotoxicity of the juice. Should be rinsed off after 30 minutes.||Allergies: People with known allergy to other plants in the Liliaceae family (onions, garlic, tulips) may have allergic reactions to aloe. Delayed allergic reactions - hives and rash - may develop with prolonged use.</properties>
		<usage>Use for dandruff.||Juice of fleshy leaves is usually mixed with gogo by Filipino women and used to prevent falling of fair or as a cure for baldness.||Juice from leaves mixed with wine used to preserve the hair.||In the Philippines, leaves used to poultice edema associated with beriberi.||Juice from leaves mixed with milk used for dysentery and pains of the kidney.||Fresh juice expressed from the leaves is spread on skin burns, scalds, scrapes, sunburn and wounds.||Burns and scalds: Use ointment made by mixing equal amounts of powdered aloe and coconut oil.||Used for wound healing.||For conjunctivitis, leaf juice is applied to the outer eyelid.||Used for sprains, sore throat.||In small doses, used as a tonic; in larger doses, as aperient; and in still larger doses, drastically so; it is also used as emmenagogue and cholagogue.||In small doses, considered stomachic tonic; in large doses, as purgative.||In Costa Rica, the mucilaginous pulp of leaves is used as purgative.||For contusions or local edema, bruised fresh leaves are applied as poultice over affected areas.||For alopecia and falling hair, remove the spines, cut leaves and rub directly on the scalp. The juice of fresh leave may be mixed with gogo and used as a shampoo.||Juice mixed with coconut milk used for dysentery and kidney pains.||For bruises, equal parts of juice and alcohol are applied to affected areas.||For hemorrhoids, cuticle from leaves used as suppository for hemorrhoids.||In India and the Antilles the alcoholic tincture of inspissated juice is used for bruises, contusions and ecchymoses.||In the Arabian peninsula, used for diabetes.||For burns and scalds, an ointment is prepared by mixing 2 drams of powdered aloe with 2 drams.||Also used for herpes simplex sores, tendinitis, dandruff, menstrual cramps, acne, stomatitis, varicose veins, warts, hemorrhoids.||Used in combination with licorice roots to treat eczema and psoriasis.||Benefits are derived from a combination of all active components; the aqueous form provides the most benefits.||Leaf jelly used for various cosmetic and new-age concoctions for pimples, acne, stomatitis, hemorrhoidal itching, superficial burns. Aloe gel is a common household remedy for minor cuts, burns and sunburns.||Salicylic acid content can inhibit prostaglandin and thromboxane formation by blocking the arachidonic acid cascade.||UV-B protection through cinnamic acid.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted.||Cultivated for ornamental and medicinal use.||Ingredients to many commercial hair/cosmetic products.||Gels, capsules, extracts in the cybermarket.</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>