<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Kolitis</name>
		<sci_name>Amaranthus viridis||Euxolus caudatus||Euxolus viridis||Amaranthus gracilis||Amaranthus polystachys</sci_name>
		<common_name>Bauan (Bon.)||Halom (Tag., Bis.)||Halunapa (Sul.)||Kadiapa (Mag.)||Kalunai (Ilk.)||Kilitis (Bik.)||Kolitis (Tag.)||Kulitis (Tag.)||Nasi (It.)||Siitan (Ilk.)||Sitan (Ib.)||Amaranth (Engl.)||Green amaranth (Engl.)||Slender amaranth (Engl.)||Wild amaranth (Engl.)||Zhou guo xian (Chin.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>BENGALI: Ban note, Bon note.||CHINESE: Lu xian, Ye xian, Niao xian, Kang xian, Ye xian cai, Shan xing cai.||FRENCH: Amarante verte.||GERMAN: Grüner Amarant.||GREEK: Depto vlito.||GUJARATI: Dhinmado.||HINDI: Chauraiya, Jangali chaulai, Jungali chaulayi.||JAPANESE: Aobiyu, Honaga inu biyu.||KANNADA: Cheakeerae soppu, Chilikiraesoppu, Dagglisoppu, , Dagglarive soppu, Eere soppu.||KOREAN: Cheong bi reum.||MALAY: Bayan hedjo.||MALAYALAM: Cerhiraa, Kuppacheera, Kuppacheera, Mullanchira, Serucira.||MARATHI: Lhanamat, Ran bhaji.||ORIYA: Levitiakoda.||PORTUGUESE: Cararu, Carurú-comum, Carurú-de-mancha, Carurú-de-porco, Carurú-de-soldado (Brazil).||RUSSIAN: Shiritsa zelenaia.||SANSKRIT: Gandira, Thanduliya, Vishaghna.||SPANISH: Bledo, Quelite verd (Mexico).||TAMIL: Iruvati, Iruvatikkirai, Kollaikkirai, Kuppai keerai, Kuppaikkirai, Sinna keerai, Vakucakkirai.||TELUGU: Chailaka thot kura, Chilaka thotakoora.||THAI: Phak hom, Phak khom, Phak khom hat.||VIETNAMESE: D?n xanh.</vernacular>
		<properties>Uray is an erect, smooth, branched unarmed herb, 30 to 60 centimeters high. Leaves are alternate, ovate, long-petioled, 4 to 10 centimeters long, obtuse tip, usually notched, base truncate or decurrent. Flowers are very small, densely disposed, green, 1 millimeter long. Sepals are 5, or 1 to 3, ovate to linear, often aristate. Inflorescences are terminal, axillary, simple or panicled, interrupted spikes. Fruits are compressed, indehiscent or circumcised utricles. Seeds are black or brown, orbicular.</properties>
		<usage>The therapeutic properties and dosage are very nearly identical to Amaranthus spinosus. (Uray)||Philippine Negritos apply bruised leaves directly to eczema, psoriasis and rashes.||Poultice of leaves for inflammations, boils and abscesses.||Use for acne and for skin cleansing.||Infusion of plant has been used as a diuretic and galactagogue.||Used for snake bites and scorpion stings.||Decoction of plant used for dysentery and inflammation.||In Ayurveda, used for treatment of diabetes.||In India, stem used as antidote for snake bites. Leaves used for scorpion stings. Traditionally used for constipation, inflammation, eczema, bronchitis, anemia and leprosy.||In Nepal, infusion of powdered seeds of flower used for stomach problems. Seeds also used in pregnant women to lessen labor pains.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>