<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Payang-payang</name>
		<sci_name>Desmodium pulchellum||Hedysarum pulchellum||Dicerma pulchellum||Zornia pulchella||Phyllodium pulchellum||Meibomia pulchella</sci_name>
		<common_name>Gaan-gaan (Sul.)||Kalaikai (C. Bis.)||Kalaykay (C. Bis.)||Payang-payang (Tag.)||Angels locks (Engl.)||Pai qian cao (Chin.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>ASSAMESE: Ursi.||BENGALI: Jutasalpani.||CAMBODIAN: Ang-prom, Prae kraoy.||CHINESE: Pai qian shu, Huan ye xiao huai hua, Long lin cao, Pai qian cao, Jian ye a po qian, Wu shi ye, Lin wan zii shu, Ya po qian.||HINDI: Jatsalpan.||INDONESIAN: Apa-apa, Apa-apa sapi, Ketipes.||LAOTIAN: Ked linz no:yz.||MALAYSIAN: Serengan kechil.||SANSKRIT: Lodhrah, Lodram.||TELUGU: Karrantinta, Kondontinta, Sarivi.||THAI: Klet plaa chon, Yaa song plong, Yaa klet lin.||VIETNAMESE: Chu[oox]i ti[eef]n, d[oof]ng ti[eef]n.</vernacular>
		<properties>Payang-payang is an erect undershrub, 0.5 to 1.5 meters in height. Leaves are 3-foliate. Leaflets are finely hairy beneath, the terminal one being oblong, 8 to 13 centimeters long, and more than twice as large as the two lateral ones. Inflorescence is terminal and axillary, and 8 to 25 centimeters long. Flowers are white and about 6 millimeters long, umbellate or fascicled, hidden by the distichous, orbicular bracts, which are 1 to 1.5 centimeters in diameter. Stamens are 10, upper one free, other 9 united. Ovary is few- to many-ovuled, superior. Fruits are pods, oblong, hairy and usually of 2, rarely 1- or 3 joints.</properties>
		<usage>In the Philippines, leaves are applied to ulcers.||In Java, the leaves are applied to pocks.||Decoction of dried leaves used for colds and fever.||Decoction of dried roots used for malaria, swelling and enlargement of liver and spleen, rheumatism,bone pains, and swelling due to contusion or sprain.||Decoction of charred roots used for excessive menstrual flow.||Malays use a decoction of roots after childbirth.||Decoction of bark for diarrhea, eye afflictions.||Decoction of bark used for hemorrhages, diarrhea, poisoning, and eye diseases.||Decoction of flowers for bile and liver afflictions.||In India, paste of root mixed with sugar candy used for abdominal and chest burning discomforts.||In Bangladesh, bark decoction used in hemorrhage diarrhea, poisoning and eye diseases. Flowers used in biliousness.||In Andhra Pradesh, India, leaves used for wounds.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>