<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Katakataka</name>
		<sci_name>Bryophyllum pinnatum||Kalanchoe pinnata||Cotyledon pinnata</sci_name>
		<common_name>Abisrana (Ilk.)||Aritana (Bik.)||Balangbang (If.)||Inginga (Ig.)||Kapal-kapal (Sul.)||Karitana (Bis)||Kokoeng (Bon.)||Lapak-lapak (Sul.)||Putputok (Bon.)||Siempre viva||Angelica (Sp.)||Air plant (Engl.)||Cathedral bells (Engl.)||Miracle plant (Engl.)||Mother of thousands (Engl.)||Live-leaf-of-resurrection plant (Engl.)||Lao di sheng gen (Chin.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>BRUNEI: Bendingin, Serigen.||BURMA: Yoekiyapinba.||INDONESIA: Daun sejk, Buntiris, Sosor bebek.||LAOS: Pount tay, Poun po.||MALAYSIA: Sedingin, Seringing, Setawar padang.||THAILAND: Benchachat, Ton tai bai pen, Khwum taai ngaai pen.||VIETNAM: C[aa]y thu[oos]c b[or]ng, C[aa]y tr[uw] [owf]ng sinh, l[aj]c c[ij]a sinh c[aw]n</vernacular>
		<properties>Katakataka is an erect, more or less branched, smooth, succulent herb, 0.4 to 1.4 meters in height. Leaves are simple or pinnately compound, with the leaflets elliptic, usually about 10 centimeters long, thick, succulent, and scalloped margins. Plantlets grow along the notches of the leaf margins which can develop while still attached to the plant or when detached, a fascinating characteristic that earns its name. Flowers are cylindric, and pendulous in a large, terminal panicle. Calyx is tubular, cylindric, inflated, brownish or purplish, 3.5 to 4 centimeters long. Corolla is tubular, about 5 centimeters long, inflated at the base, and then constricted, the exserted parts being reddish or purplish and thelobes tapering to a point. Fruit is a follicle with many seeds.</properties>
		<usage>Leaves used as astringent, antiseptic, and counterirritant against poisonous insect bites.||Pounded fresh material is applied as a poultice for a variety of conditions: Sprains, eczema, 		  		  infections, burns, carbuncle and erysipelas.||Leaves, made pliable by hold over fire, are applied to wounds, bruises, boils; also, used as poultice or power in bad ulcers.||Juice is mixed with lard and used for diarrhea, dysentery, cholera, and phthisis.||Pounded leaves are applied as poultices to the soles of the feet to stop hemorrhages.||Leaves are used as topicals in dislocation, ecchymoses, callosities.||Leaves, pounded and mixed with salt, used as plaster and applied to stomach to relieve enuresis||For boils, the whole leaf is pressed by hand, to and fro, until it becomes moist with the leaf extract. A small opening is made in the middle of the leaf which is then placed on the boil with hole over the pointing of the abscess.||For asthma, leaves of leaves places in hot water for 15 minutes, then juice squeezed out of the leaves, and drunk.||Juice of leaves used in bilious diarrhea and lithiasis.||In Ayurveda, useful in vitiated conditions of vata and pitta, cuts, wounds, hemorrhoids, menorrhagia, boils, sloughing ulcers, burns and scalds, diarrhea, dysentery, headaches, vomiting, bronchitis.||In Puerto Rico, leaf juice used as diuretic.||Leaves are rubbed or tied on the head for headaches.||Leaf decoction usually taken to lower blood pressure.||Leaf juice used for earache and ophthalmia.||In Sierre Leon, cough medicine is made from the roots.||In Brazil leaves, heated over fire and mixed with oil, are used as emollient and refrigerant for facial swelling associated with neuralgia or tooth trouble. Also, used for asthma and bronchitis.||In Jamaica, leaves used for coughs and colds. Sometimes, it is mixed with salt or honey, for headaches, colds, bronchial||In Africa, used for earaches, eye problems, and as diuretic.||In China used for rheumatoid arthritis, bruises, burns and ulcers.||In Nigeria, plant is considered sedative, wound-healing, diuretic, anti-inflammatory, and cough suppressant. Leaf juice used to treat boils and skin ulcers. Plant used for intestinal parasit bronchitis, pneumonia.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>