<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Achuete</name>
		<sci_name>Bixa acuminata||Bixa americana||Bixa katagensis||Bixa odorata||Bixa orellana||Bixa platycarpa||Bixa purpurea||Bixa tinctoria||Bixa upatensis||Hong mu</sci_name>
		<common_name>Achiti (Ilk.)||Achote (Tag.)||Achoete (Tagb.)||Atchuete (Tag., Sbl., Bik., P. Bis., Ilk.)||Achwete (Tag.)||Asoti (Ibn.)||Asiute (Sbl.)||Apatut (Gad.)||Asuete (Tag.)||Asuite (Ilk.)||Asuti (Tag.)||Atseuete (Tag.)||Atsuite (Ilk.)||Chanang (Sul.)||Chotes (S. L. Bis.)||Janang (Sul.)||Sotis (C. Bis.)||Annatto (Engl.)||Lipstick plant (Engl.)||Yan zhi mu (Chin.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>BENGALI: Latka||CHINESE: Yan zhi shu||DANISH: Annatobusken, Orleantræ, Smørfarvetræ.||DUTCH: Anatto, Rocou, Annotto, Achiote, Orleaan||ESTONIA: Annatopõõsa, Värvibiksa.||FINNISH: Annaatto.||FRENCH: Annato, Atole, Rocou, Rocouyer, Roucou, Roucouyer||GERMAN: Anattosamen, Annattosamen, Anattostrauch, Orleansbaum, Orleansamen, Orleanstrauch.||HINDI: Lathwa, Latkana, Sindhuri.||HUNGARIAN: Bjoul , Orleánfa, Ruku.||ITALIAN: Annatto, Anotto.||JAPANESE: Achiote, Anatoo, Anatto, Beni no ki||KHMER: Châm puu, Châm puu chrâluëk.||KOREAN: A chi o te, A na to, Bik sa sok.||LAOTIAN: Kh-am, Satii, Sômz phuu.||MALAY: Jarak belanda, Kunyit jawa, Kesumba (Indonesia), Kesumba kling (Indonesia).||MARATHI: Sendrii||NEPALESE: Sindur, Sindure.||MARATHI: Sendrii||PORTUGESE: Açafroa do Brasil, Anato, Annato, Urucú, Urucú da mata, Urucum.||RUSSIAN: Achiote, Biksa, Pomadnoe derevo.||SERBIAN: Orlean-drvo||SPANISH: Achihuite, Achiote, Achiote caspi, Achote, Bija, Bijol, Pumacua||SUNDANESE: GALUGA||SWEDISH: Annattobuske.||TAMIL: Jabra, Kongaram, Sappira.||THAI: Kam sêt, Kham faet, Kham ngae, Kham ngo, Kham thai.||VIETNAMESE: Diêù nhuôm, H?t di?u màu.</vernacular>
		<properties>Next to caramel, annatto is the world-s most important natural colorant yielding yellow to red colors. There is global commercial production of the seed, estimated in 1990 at 10,000 tons per year; Brazil being the largest exported. Atsuete is a tree reaching 4 to 6 meters. Leaves are entire, alternate with long petioles, ovate, 8 to 20 centimeters long, 5 to 12 centimeters wide, with a broad and heart-shaped base, and a pointed tip. The flowers are white or pinkish, 4 to 6 centimeters diameter, 4 to 6 centimeters in diameter on terminal panicles. Fruits are spiny capsules, ovoid or rounded, reddish brown, about 4 centimeters long, and covered with long, slender and soft spines. Fruit dry and split open in two parts exposing many small red seeds covered with a dye-yielding red pulp.</properties>
		<usage>For small burns: Wash the leaves with soap and water. Boil 10 leaves in 5 glasses of water; cool. Soak the burn area for 10 minutes, once a day.||The pulp of the seeds, immediately applied to, prevents blistering and scarring. Pulp also used to treat bleeding, dysentery, gonorrhea, constipation and fever.||The seeds, ground and boiled, also used for burns. Mixed with coconut, is applied to the throat.||Decoction of bark used for febrile catarrh.||Fresh seeds when moistened produce a reddish colored juice that is applied to red rashes.||The seeds are used as antidote for cassava and J. urcas poisoning.||Fine powder that covers the seeds is used as hemostatic, and internally as stomachic.||In French Guiana, infusion of leaves used as purgative in dysentery.||Leaves used as febrifuge in Cambodia.||Decoction of leaves used as gargle for sore throat.||Seed oil used for leprosy.||The achuete dye used with lime for the treatment of erysipelas.||Also used for wound healing, regulation of heavy menses, and thinning hair.||The leaf, bruised with the head of a "walis-tingting" (broom made from frond ribs of the coconut leaves), mixed with warm coconut oil is applied on the forehead for headaches.||An infusion of the leaves used as purgative.||Poultice of leaves are diuretic and used for treatment of gonorrhea||Mucilage produced from infusion of fresh branches used a emollient in the Antilles.|| Leaves for snake bites.||Extract of leaves, barks and roots used as antidote for poisoning from Manihot esculenta, J. curcas, and Hura crepitans.||Decoction of leaves for nausea and vomiting.||In traditional Peruvian medicine, used to treat heartburn and stomach distress caused by spicy foods; also, as a vaginal antiseptic and cicatrizant.||In Uruguay seeds are ground and boiled and used on burns.||In West Indian folk medicine, used for diabetes mellitus.||In Guatemala used for treatment of gonorrhea.||Female aphrodisiac in the Amazonia.Folkloric||For small burns: Wash the leaves with soap and water. Boil 10 leaves in 5 glasses of water; cool. Soak the burn area for 10 minutes, once a day.||The pulp of the seeds, immediately applied to, prevents blistering and scarring. Pulp also used to treat bleeding, dysentery, gonorrhea, constipation and fever.||The seeds, ground and boiled, also used for burns. Mixed with coconut, is applied to the throat.||Decoction of bark used for febrile catarrh.||Fresh seeds when moistened produce a reddish colored juice that is applied to red rashes.||The seeds are used as antidote for cassava and J. urcas poisoning.||Fine powder that covers the seeds is used as hemostatic, and internally as stomachic.||In French Guiana, infusion of leaves used as purgative in dysentery.||Leaves used as febrifuge in Cambodia.||Decoction of leaves used as gargle for sore throat.||Seed oil used for leprosy.||The achuete dye used with lime for the treatment of erysipelas.||Also used for wound healing, regulation of heavy menses, and thinning hair.||The leaf, bruised with the head of a "walis-tingting" (broom made from frond ribs of the coconut leaves), mixed with warm coconut oil is applied on the forehead for headaches.||An infusion of the leaves used as purgative.||Poultice of leaves are diuretic and used for treatment of gonorrhea.||Mucilage produced from infusion of fresh branches used a emollient in the Antilles.||Leaves for snake bites.||Extract of leaves, barks and roots used as antidote for poisoning from Manihot esculenta, J. curcas, and Hura crepitans.||Decoction of leaves for nausea and vomiting.||In traditional Peruvian medicine, used to treat heartburn and stomach distress caused by spicy foods; also, as a vaginal antiseptic and cicatrizant.||In Uruguay seeds are ground and boiled and used on burns.||In West Indian folk medicine, used for diabetes mellitus.||In Guatemala used for treatment of gonorrhea.||Female aphrodisiac in the Amazonia.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted.||Small scale local cultivation for condiment and food colorant.||Worldwide production of annatto seeds for commercial and home use.</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>