<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Granada</name>
		<sci_name>Punica granatum||Punica multiflora||Punica nana||Punica spinosa</sci_name>
		<common_name>Dalima (Sul.)||Granada (Span., Tag.)||Pomegranate (Engl.)||Shi liu (Chin.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>CROATIAN : Sipak.||DANISH : Granatæble.||DUTCH : Granaatappel.||ESTONIAN : Harilik granaadipuu.||FRENCH : Ecorce de grenade (rind), Ecorce de grenadier (écorce-bark), Grenade (fruit), Grenadier (tree).||GERMAN : Granatapfel, Granatapfelbaum, Granatapfelstrauch, Granatwurzelrinde (rind).||GREEK : Rodi, Rodia.||ITALIAN : Granato , Granato a frutto dolce, Melagrana, Melograno, Pomogranato.||JAPANESE : Zakuro, Zakuro, Zakuro.||KOREAN : Seog ryu||MALAY : Buah delima, Delima (Indonesia), Delima (Bali).||NEPALESE : Anaar, Daariim.||NORWEGIAN : Granateple.||RUSSIAN : Granat.||SANSKRIT : Darimba, Madhubiija.||SPANISH : Granada, Granado, Mangrano.||THAI : Ma ko, Thap thim.</vernacular>
		<properties>Pomegranate has been in traditional medicinal use for more than 3000 years. Ancient and mystical, it has been written about in the Old Testament of the Bible, the Jewish Torah, and the Babylonian Talmud as a sacred fruit with powers that bestow fertility, abundance, and good luck. It is also part of the iconography of rituals, art, and mythology - the personal emblem of the Roman Emperor, Maximilian, the symbol and heraldic device of the ancient city of Granada in Spain. Granada is a shrub growing 2 to 3 meters high. Branchlets are slender and 4-angled. Leaves are oblong-lanceolate to oblong-elliptic; 4 to 6 centimeters long, short-stalked, and pointed at both ends. Flowers are red and showy, usually with six segments in the calyx which are 2.5 to 3 centimeters long. Petals are obovate, about 2 centimeters long. Stamens are numerous. Fruit is rounded, reddish-yellow or purplish, 7 to 10 centimeters in diameter. Rind is thin, tough, and brittle. Fruit contains numerous seeds, each seed surrounded by a watery, translucent, flavorful pinkish-red pulp.</properties>
		<usage>Decoction of root bark used for tapeworm.||Decoction of tender leaves used as gargle for buccal afflictions.||Decoction of roots used for tuberculosis, chronic debility, chronic feverishness.||Decoction of leaves used as eyewash.||Powdered flower buds used for bronchitis.||Decoction of juice of the flower with equal parts of Cynodon dactylon used to stop epistaxis and as gargle.||Infusion of flowers used as vermifuge.||The bark (alkaloids) used for tapeworms.||Rind of the fruit and flowers, combined with aromatics such as cloves, cinnamon, coriander or pepper, are used as astringent in bowel affections not associated with tenesmus.||Decoction of the dried rind of the fruit used for stomach pains and dysentery; infusion used for colitis.||Juice believed to be beneficial for leprosy.||Bark, leaves and immature fruit (tannins) used as astringents for diarrhea, dysentery and hemorrhages.||Dried pulverized flower buds used for bronchitis.||In India, rind of fruit used for diarrhea.||Juice of fresh fruit used for dyspepsia and as a cooling and thirst-quenching drink for fevers.||The Chinese and Annamites use the rind of the fruit and root bark as vermifuge.||In Mexico, decoction of flowers used a gargle for throat inflammation.||In Indian traditional medicine, use for diarrhea.||In Myanmar, decoction of dried bark of stem and root used as taeniafuge.||In Iran, flowers used as remedy for cut wounds, bronchitis, diarrhea, digestive problems, male sex power reconstitution. In Unani medicine, used for diabetes.||In China, flowers used for premature graying of hair in young men.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted</availability>
	</item>
</herbal>