<herbal>
	<item>
		<name>Okra</name>
		<sci_name>Abelmoschus esculentus||Hibiscus esculentis</sci_name>
		<common_name>Okra (Tag., Engl.)||Gumbo (Engl.)||Lady fingers (Engl.)||Huang su kui (Chin.)</common_name>
		<vernacular>ARABIC: Bâmyah.||CHINESE: Ka fei huang kui, Yue nan zhi ma, Yang jiao dou, Hu ma, Qiu kui.||BURMESE: You padi.||CROATIAN: Jedilna oslez.||DANISH: Okra.||DUTCH: Okra.||FRENCH: Gombo, Gombeaud, Bamie-okra, Ketmie comestible (Belgium).||GERMAN: Ocker.||GREEK: Bamies. Bamia.||HEBREW: Bamiya, Hibiscus ne´echal.||HINDI: Bhindee, Dheras, Bandakai, Vendakai.||HUNGARIAN: Gombó, Bámia.||ITALIAN: Gombo, Ocra, Bammia d´Egitto, Corna di Greci .||JAPANESE: Amerika neri, Kiku kimo, Okura.||KHMER: Pôôt barang.||KOREAN: Oh k´u ra.||LAOTIAN: Khüa ngwàng.||MALAY: Bendi, Kacang bendi, Kacang lender, Sayur bendi , Kacang lendir , Kachang bendi, Kopi arab.||NEPALESE: Van lasun.||NORWEGIAN: Grønsakhibisk||POLISH : Czyli okra, Ketmia jadalna.||PORTUGUESE: Gambô, Quiabo, Quibombô, Quibombó.||ROMANIAN: Bame.||RUSSIAN: Bamiia.||SANSKRIT: Tindisa.||SPANISH: Gombo, Ají turco, Quimbombo, Ocra, Ruibarbo.||TAMIL: Vendaikkaay.||THAI: Krachiap, Ton krachiap, Krachiap khieo, Krachiap mon, Bakhua mun.||TURKISH: Bamya .||URDU: Bhindii.</vernacular>
		<properties>Okra is a coarse, erect, branched, more or less hairy, annual herb, 0.6 to 1.5 meters high. Leaves are long-petioled, orbicular or orbicular-ovate, about 25 centimeters long or less; with a heart-shaped base; the margins, 3- to 5-lobed. Petioles are equal to the blade in length or longer. Flowers are axillary and solitary; corolla, large and yellow, and inside, deep purple at the base. Fruit is elongated, 10 to 25 centimeters long, 1.5 to 3 centimeters in diameter, tapering to a blunt point and containing rows of rounded, kidney shaped seeds.</properties>
		<usage>Decoction of roots and leaves as a tea or for washing.||Decoction of young fruit useful for catarrh, urinary problems.||Syrup from mucilaginous fruit used for sore throat.||Infusion of roots used for syphilis.||Poultice of roots and leaves for wound healing.||Young pods for fevers, difficult urination and diarrhea.||Decoction of roots for headaches, varicose veins, arthritis, fevers.||Decoctions of leaves for abdominal pain.||Leaves also useful as emollient poultice.||Mucilage prepared from roots and leaves used for gonorrhea.||Fruit used as demulcent in gonorrhea and dysuria.||Paste of seeds, mixed with milk, used for pruritic skin lesions.||In Turkey, leaves used in preparation of medicine to reduce inflammation.||In India, decoction of young fruit used for catarrh and urinary troubles. Also used for fevers, catarrhal attacks, genitourinary irritations such as dysuria, gonorrhea and leucorrhea, and in cases associated with scaling, pain, and difficulty passing urine.||Bland mucilage used for dysentery, usually as soup.||Tender pods eaten for spermatorrhea.||Mucilage from from fruits and seeds of fresh, bruised capsules make an efficient, emollient poultice.||Fruit decoction used as soothing demulcent remedy for throat irritations associated with coughing.||Infusion of toasted seeds used for sudorific effect.||Hindus consider the aromatic seeds as cooling, tonic, and carminative.||In Annam, seeds considered antispasmodic.||In the Antilles and Guiana, seeds considered stimulant, cordial, and antispasmodic.</usage>
		<availability>Wild-crafted.||Perennial market produce. </availability>
	</item>
</herbal>